# Kenrick M. Ramsay

I create clean, functional interfaces for web and mobile. I'm passionate about good design. And intuitive user experience. In my design practice, my goal is always to bring together the needs of a business with those of its customers and users.

( kenrickramsay.com

kenrickramsay@yahoo.com

347.834.1580

## **Education**

**School of Visual Arts |** Master's of Interactive Design September 2018 -

**Johnson & Wales University |** B.S Graphic Design & Digital Media September 2010 - May 2014

# Experience

#### Jr. Designer | Good2BSocial | November 2017 - Present

I collaborated with account managers in redesign legal and medical firms' websites. I created wireframes, user flows, and designs for small to large-scale websites from start to finish to be interactive, user-friendly, and SEO compliant. Mocked up prototypes for tested and gave presentations to clients. Determined the number of page templates to adhere to the development budget and tested for QA.

## Freelance Designer | September 2011 - Present

Worked as a freelance designer for multiple projects (web development, brand identity, illustrations, and visual design), clients include CSRI, Knewtown & SalesGraphics.

## Lead Designer | Transit Wireless | October 2015 - August 2017

I redesigned the company's branding using illustrations for infographics, mockups for WiFi platform design and web development for Transit Wireless's new website. The newly designed brand identity including new external & internal company logos, branding templates, promotional materials, websites, and social media accounts. Created graphics, slide templates and PPT materials for RFP/board documents, external client presentations and collateral for use by all departments.

#### Creative Design Intern | MKTG Inc. | June 2015 - August 2015

Assisted the in-house Graphic Designers with the production of marketing collateral for print and digital mediums in the form of layout design, photo manipulation, and signage. Developed a promotional advertisement for upcoming events and experiences that the client hosted. Collaborated with designers to develop novel ideas for unique and new experiences for our clients.

## UI Design Intern | nivo. | November 2014 - March 2015

Worked with the Marketing & Development Team to design new user interfaces for a mobile product to be released on both Apple app & Google Play stores. Designed new interfaces, including a new library and call-to-actions. Conducted research to establish business and user requirements, and delivered through design specs for engineers to implement.

# Skills

#### Design

Co-Design Journey Mapping **Empath Mapping** Storyboarding Wireframing Prototyping Illustration & UI graphics Visual Design Interface Design User Experience Design & Research User Interface Design User flows & Concept Sketches **Brand Development** Front End Development Marketing Strategy Primary & Secondary Research

#### **Design Tools**

AfterEffects
Framer
Illustrator
InDesign
InVision
Origami
Photoshop
Principle
Sketch
XD
Premiere

#### **Programming**

HTML | CSS JavaScript Sass |Scss MySQL PHP Python P5JS C++ | Processing | Arduino